<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Exploring the world through data analysis and machine learning</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Planning Support Team Resources in Start-ups Using Statistics</title>
        
          <description>Planning staff allocation for customer support can be challenging since great support is essential for company success but it can consume large portion of usually limited budget. This can be particularly true in smaller companies and start-ups where the case volume significantly fluctuates and the staff also needs to work on other projects besides support.

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 10:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /Team-Plannning</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Team-Plannning</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Python function to automatically transform skewed data in Pandas DataFrame</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;When I stumble on a cool new dataset, I often find myself excitedly prototyping a quick machine learning models to see what I can get out of the latest find. This is mostly easy thanks to plenty awesome packages such as scikit-learn or Keras. As a result, I spend most of my prototyping effort on cleaning and transforming the data.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /Skewness_Auto_Transform</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Skewness_Auto_Transform</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Support Data Generator in Python</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;We all have been there - it is Sunday evening, you have couple of fresh ideas for a new customer centric strategy and you want to test how it would hold up in the real world. Unfortunately, it might be hard to get real or at least somewhat realistic customer support ticket datasets for specific business models and company size.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /Support-Data-Generator</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Support-Data-Generator</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>First Test Post</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;TEST POST iFrame 2 goes here&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /Test-Post</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Test-Post</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
